Robert Whittaker

Video & Music Producer | Software Engineer | Music Typesetter

Mobile: 07930592148 | Email: rbrwhittaker@yahoo.com

Portfolio - https://robertwhittaker-videoproduction-portfolio.netlify.app/

Summary

Fast working, talented video editor with 4+ years of professional experience creating lyric and promo videos. Outstanding reputation for speedy delivery and exceeding expectations, resulting in all clients returning for more videos. Seeking professional video/image editing work outside of the music industry to develop my software skills.

Software

- Premiere Pro
- Photoshop
- After Effects
- Microsoft Office
- Sibelius
- Cubase / ProTools / Logic Pro

Professional Experience

Royal Mail - 2020-2021

During the COVID-19 pandemic, as the music industry was on pause, I was a Postman for Newport, South Wales.

Freelance Work - 2015-2020

- <u>Video Producer</u>: Working one-to-one with clients to produce promo/lyric videos using Adobe Premier Pro and After Effects. Including still image editing as part of video and working with band logos with Photoshop
- <u>Music Producer/Sound Engineer</u>: Recording studios Rockfield Studios (Monmouth), Cardiff University School of Music, Green Rooms (Pontypridd), Unit 13 (Tredegar). Software: Pro Tools and Logic Pro.
- <u>Music Editing/Typesetting</u>: Setting music examples for publication in academic books and journal articles. Software: Sibelius Music Notation.
- <u>Composer & Performer</u>: EP of original songs plus recorded singles with various artists incl. session work. Guitarist/vocalist/cellist– live concert performances around Wales/UK. Software: Cubase (composing)
- Lower Machen Festival: Sound and lighting engineer, stage construction, front of house staff.
- TV/Film extra: Casualty (BBC One drama series), How I live now (2013, dir. Kevin Macdonald)

Education

BSc (Hons) Creative Industries (Popular Music Technology) University of South Wales 2012-2015